Uditesh Jha

Toronto, ON | (416) 837-7480 | uditesh24jha@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

Professional Summary

Technology-driven software engineer with 3+ years of professional experience in a fast-paced and agile workspace. A team player with a keen eye for detail and a commitment to on-time project delivery in collaborative environments. Adept in handling complex challenges and learning new technologies.

Education

Advanced Diploma, Software Engineering Technician | *Centennial College, CA*Ontario Graduate Certificate, Web Development | *Humber College, CA*B.Tech, Computer Science & Engineering | *Parul University, IND*Jan 2022 – Aug 2022

Jan 2021 – Dec 2021

Aug 2015 – May 2019

Experience

Associate Software Engineer | Activous Solutions, Gujarat, IND

June 2020 - Dec 2021

- Experienced with developing new features, solving bugs, debugging, and extensive testing.
- Involved in the development of an invoice module life cycle; including analysis, requirements gathering, application development, testing, deployment, system and user documentation, user training, and application support/maintenance.
- · Hands-on experience in Java 8, Spring Boot framework, Restful APIs, MongoDB, and Mongoose.
- Implemented a cutting-edge database migration strategy that increased the database performance by 20%.
- Trained and provided technical guidance to juniors, leading to a **15%** improvement in code quality and a **15%** reduction in software development bugs.

Junior Software Engineer | SRKay Consulting Group, Gujarat, IND

Feb 2019 - June 2020

- Hands-on experience with Spring, GitLab, Jenkins, Kubernetes, Hibernate, and SQL Server.
- Worked on the Accounting Management System module of the Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) tool
 which was the internal project of the SRK exports.
- Involved in solving bugs, building Junit tests, and completing tasks in JIRA.
- Qualified in working with Restful web services and microservices.
- Achieved **100**% on-time delivery of functionalities for the external project by using an Agile scrum environment where I directly reported to the head of technology.

Internship

Intern Android Developer | Iglobe Consulting, Gujarat, IND

July 2018 - Sept 2018

- · Re-designed the IOS application in Adobe XD for the Android application.
- · Involved in developing an Android application for Scooter's coffee shop in Android Studio.

Intern Java Developer | World4Engineers, Gujarat, IND

Jan 2018 - June 2018

- Experienced with Java servlets and Java server pages (JSPs), JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, jQuery, and MySQL.
- Collaborated with cross-functional team to design and deploy versatile software solutions, driving a 10% increase in customer loyalty.

Technical Skills

- Programming Languages: Java, JavaScript C#, Python
- Framework and Libraries: Spring Boot, Hibernate, Mongoose, Node.js, Express.js, React.js
- Databases: MySQL, SQL Server, MongoDB, PostgreSQL
- Technologies: Git, AWS (EC2, Lambda, ELB), Docker, Kubernetes